That's a pretty wild thumbnail,
and that's completely AI generated.
And the reason I'm even doing this video
of the cuff is really this industry, my
industry,
this kind of business mentorship content,
it's full of fakes as it is. People
that may be just copying other people's
videos,
maybe even the transcripts.
The most common is people that
ran businesses that weren't really
that profitable, but then they go into the
business of helping businesses charge
loads of money and then make loads of
money
that way.
And they're trying to sell you the skills
of operating a business when
they only made their money from the
business to business, not the business to
consumer. And considering now
that you just need to tell AI to give you
a prompt
to put you on the beach with a six-pack in
front of a Lamborghini, and it takes 25
seconds to do it, this industry
is only going to get worse.
Now, they say you either die the hero
or live long enough to become the villain.
I've been doing these business mentorship
days in person since 2018,
and I never really fancied doing it online
because I saw just kind of how
sleazy the industry is.
There's something I want to get off my
chest.
It's actually a criticism
that I got this week of someone requesting
a refund from
my course,
which doesn't exactly strike you as the
kind of
topic you want to talk about. If anything,
the very last thing I should be talking
about is an unhappy customer
when at the end of the day,
I'm here to try and
promote my services on the course.
But anyway, the person in the course said,
"I've joined your course, and it's
pretty much everything
that you talk about on YouTube.
And on YouTube, it's free."
And this really annoyed me because, yeah,
of course, it's going to have to be
heavily and closely aligned to what
is on YouTube.
If it wasn't, that would be a problem.
The fact it is shouldn't be a problem.
But then I kind of slept on it, and I
was thinking about it.
And being a business person,
the thing that I enjoy more than anything
on a
day-to-day basis is winning over business.
I've not always been like this.
I've never been entrepreneurial.
I used to work in shopping centers.
You know the people
that stop you as you're trying to go about
your day doing
shopping? That was me.
I used to get £7 commission a sale, and
if I did 10 sales in
a day, I'd get £9 commission a sale.
I worked in door to door for a gas
and electric company.
So I've always enjoyed winning the sale.
So then I thought, hold on.
Am I putting maybe too much effort into
the YouTube, so that
when people get to the
course, they're like, "Hold on,
I've heard this before"?
And then I was like, "Nah." And this
is my way of justifying it.
There are two reasons I'm making content
on YouTube.
50% to win you over.
As someone that's not yet using me as a
business mentor, I want to win you over.
And the day you want to purchase the
course,
I want you actually kind of to feel
like even if I did screw you over
and deliver a shit
product, which I don't, I hope I don't,
that you'd go, "Fair enough.
He's helped me so much with the free
content that that's okay."
But that's worst
case scenario.
And I suppose one thing
that I'm really keen on is giving so much
away for free that you should know
objectively whether or not I'm the right
person for you to choose.
And the second thing is this.
A lot of the content I put out, written,
video, whatever, is actually to
G up, and here's the word,
remind people within my
existing program. This
is my favorite Alex Hormozi quote.
I think a lot of the stuff he says,
no offense,
I just can't relate to it. I'm like, "Bro,
you're jacked.
You got a great hairline,
better than mine.
You made more money than me.
Questionable fashion sense. I admire you,
but I can't get on with any of your
advice. I bought both your books,
didn't really rate them." But he goes,
"People
need to be reminded more than they need to
be educated." And I was like, wow,
validated what I've been thinking.
Most of the stuff I'm doing on YouTube
is actually to remind the people within my
course what they need to be doing because
they've done the modules, they've been
through the courses, everything.
And I suppose that
is kind of what brings me on to the final
point of this.
Should you hire me or anyone else,
you're not actually paying us to teach
stuff you
don't know.
Some of the stuff you don't know,
but 80% of it you actually do
know. The reason you pay us is so
that you do it.
I come from a background of personal
training. That is exactly what we did.
People know they need to follow a program.
People know they can go to ChatGPT
and get a program written for them.
The reason they pay a trainer
is to make sure they do it.
Skin in the game.
It's raising stakes. When you pay someone,
there are consequences to inaction.
There's a psychological term called loss
aversion, where basically,
if you're walking down the street,
dropping and losing £10 would annoy you
more than the equivalent
of finding £10. Finding £10, oh, that
was great.
Losing £10 ruined your day.
Unless you're me. £10.
Are you kidding?
That's a joke.
So the psychological pain of losing money
or giving over money is
tremendous. The same reason
that you would never think about robbing a
bank for
£10,000, would you? Nah.
But would you shave £10,000
off your tax bill? Way more likely.
Tax evasion,
way more people get caught than theft.
The reason is once you have that money,
the pain of giving it over is
psychologically worse. But this
is actually a benefit to
when you do join courses,
not the rip-offs, the people
that take your money,
don't actually teach you
anything, whatever. Say you pay me.
You now have to do what I say,
or it's a waste of money.
You know you need to make content.
I've been training in jujitsu for eight
years,
nine years. Hopefully,
I'll get my black belt next year.
And even then, people go, "Wow,
you got your black belt quick." I would
like to
think that maybe 9 out of 10 people in the
sport,
99 out of 100 people in the world,
I could physically dominate.
Why? Because I spent nine years doing it.
With content creation,
sometimes some of you make content for
three months
sporadically,
and you're wondering why you're not any
good.
It takes two years to get a blue belt,
then purple, then brown, then black.
But for some reason,
in the content creation space,
you're like, "Oh, where are my
clients?" I'm like, "Bro,
you've been doing it three months." I
was showing people
a graph, this graph earlier on,
which shows that for years, my
following was just dead.
Two and a half years,
maybe even three years,
under 4,000 followers, and then
vroom.
Facebook's at 1.1 million, Insta's at 1.4,
TikTok's at 1.8.
My content strategy never worked until it
did.
And it wasn't the algorithm that changed.
It wasn't anything that changed.
It was me that changed.
I became more confident in what I
was doing.
I got better at creating hooks.
Everything is a muscle.
The creative muscle,
the part of your brain that comes up
with an idea, goes, "Oh,
that'll make a good email. Oh,
maybe we should try this.
Oh, we write that." It's all a muscle.
And the more you train it over years,
the better it becomes.
There are a lot of gurus in this space
saying you need to hang out in Facebook
groups, DM people, jump on sales calls.
They're giving you things that
are retard proof. They are.
Because ultimately,
the business that I'm in
is giving you the hard stuff,
the stuff that takes years.
Content creation will start being
effective soon, but you're not going
to be amazing at it for quite a while.
It's going to take you months of trying
different campaigns, of getting people's
email addresses,
whether it's an asset that you give away,
autoresponder,
whatever.
And then you've got to learn how to write
good emails and to
write what is known as sales copy,
which takes a while.
I need you to not just have a few,
but dozens of videos that you thought
that were
going to do so well bomb,
and also I need for dozens of videos
that you thought
were going to bomb to do well.
I need for you to send out emotionally
charged
emails that don't get you anything.
I want you to write emails
that you didn't think would get people to
join, and then
they email you back.
I want you to get emails from people where
they go, "I've been
reading your emails for 10 months,
now I'm over the line." I need you to try
things
in your business that work,
try things that don't.
Try things that make money,
try things that lose you money.
You know what you need to be doing.
The biggest problem most of you have
is that
you're just not doing it,
and you like to hide behind the guise of,
"Maybe I need
to learn something new.
Maybe I need more techniques.
Maybe I need to watch more YouTube
videos." No, you just need to begin.
Because you have this naivety
that there is a world where you can begin
where you
don't fucking suck.
And that's just not going to happen.
So like I say, the industry,
absolutely full of plebs,
people chatting shit every
corner. The amount of fake gurus
is only going to rise.
Just zoom out from all of that
and appreciate there is no new information
that's going to come along that's going to
change anything more than you
actually starting to do the things
that I'm telling you to do
and seeing the impact
that has over time.
And you're going to massively overestimate
what you can do in
months,
and hugely underestimate what you can do
in years.
"Oh,
but I don't want to wait years." Well,
suck it up.
It took me three and a half years of
posting every day to get an online client.
It was much harder in fucking 2016 than it
is now.
So stop being a bitch.
Post something today, and then tomorrow,
and then the next
day.
Doesn't have to be a fucking
"Oppenheimer." I don't care
if you screenshot a
fucking tweet if you want to be a lazy
bastard. I don't care. Put out a reel.
I don't care if you record it on your
phone. I don't care. One a day.
If you can't put out a piece of content a
day within your niche, fuck off back to
recruitment,
because you're probably just not cut out
for this.
That fair?
Have a good day.